batchmates.com 2008-06-16

# Privacy Policy of Batchmates.com

Batchmates.com has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and usage practices. For additional information about Batchmates.com, please review our Terms of Service.  
Batchmates.com does not sell or rent your personal identification to third parties. Batchmates.com does provide your personal identification to selected, affiliated companies to allow them to perform services for members on our behalf.

**Email**

It is the policy of Batchmates.com to send our members only the types of email they elect to receive in addition to Batchmates.com customary business communications (address confirmation, renewal notifications, new product offerings, etc.). Further, it is our policy to remove members from any Batchmates.com mailing list to which they have subscribed upon request (members will continue to receive customary business communications from Batchmates.com). At any time, members can update their email preferences list via the "My Page" button. In addition, every subscribed email communication from Batchmates.com will contain clear and obvious instructions for how the member can remove himself or herself from that mailing list.

**Membership Registration**

Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor your experience at Batchmates.com, showing content that we think you might be interested in, and displaying the content according to your preferences. We do this in two ways. First, we analyze members information in aggregate- that is, we collect information about thousands of site visits and analyze it as a whole. This kind of study involves looking for trends among many visitors to Batchmates.com, rather than analyzing information about any individual member. Examples include researching which parts of the site are accessed most frequently, or determining which products are most attractive to our users. Second, we may use information gathered during your visit to help customize our communications with you.

Batchmates.com may periodically conduct individual voluntary member surveys. We encourage our members to participate in these surveys because they provide us with important information that helps us to improve the types of services we offer, and how we provide them to you. The responses we collect in online surveys are anonymous. In the end, we hope to tailor our communications with you to fit your needs- so that you receive more of what you want from us and less of what you don't want.

**Updating Your Personal Information**

Batchmates.com provides you with ways in which you can alter the personal data listed below. To make these changes, please log in and click the "My Page" tab followed by the "Profile". Once you have made the desired changes, click the Update button to lock in your changes. Follow the directions below to make changes to your personal information

You have the ability to change or correct the following information yourself:

  * Your First or Last Name 
  * Your Email Address 
  * Your Postal Address 
  * Your Password 
  * Your Email Subscriptions 
  * Your School Name, City, State, or Country 

**The Security of Your Information**

We work diligently to protect the security of your personal information, including credit card information, during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer(SSL)software, which encrypts information you input. Your data is kept in a highly secure environment protected from access by unauthorized parties. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer by ensuring you logoff when finished visiting Batchmates.com using a shared computer.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored in a browser-related file on your computer's hard drive when you use our Web site. We use cookies to improve the member experience, like allowing the member to login without typing the registered email address or registration number and password. We also use them to deliver information and fresh content specific to your interests. Cookies are widely used on most major Web sites.

 **IP Address**

Like most Internet sites, we use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information. This information is distributed to current and potential advertisers, but only in aggregate form. It does not contain information that identifies individual members.

**Advertising and Third Party Links**

Some Batchmates.com advertisers and affiliate partners may request information directly from users, or link to sites that do so. Batchmates.com has no control over its advertisers' privacy policies, and encourages users to review such policies prior to submitting any personal information to them.

Batchmates.com contains non-advertising links to a variety of third party sites to enhance the member experience. Batchmates.com has no control of either the content or privacy policies of such sites, nor should such links be considered an endorsement of these sites except where otherwise noted.

**Updates to our information practices**

From time to time, we make changes to our information practices or alter the functionality of our Web site. We always update this statement accordingly, so we encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on privacy practices at Batchmates.com.

**Abuse of Terms of Service**

We may provide your personal information to the police or other investigating agencies to assist them in the investigation of any suspected violations of law. We also have the right to share your name and contact information with our attorneys in the event of serious violations of conduct.

**Privacy policy FAQ’s**

  1. What information does batchmates.com track
  2. How does batchmates.com use the information it collects/ tracks.
  3. With whom does batchmates.com share the information it collects/ tracks.
  4. What about links to other sites?
  5. Use of cookies on the site.
  6. This sites policy on correcting, updating or removing personal information.
  7. Changes in our privacy policy.
  8. Security of your personal information.
  9. E mail Choice/ Opt-out policy
  10. Methods of contacting the site.

Please contact [www.batchmates.com](http://www.batchmates.com/) with questions regarding this statement. If the website has not responded to your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed.

  1. **About batchmates.com and the Information We Collect**

Batchmates.com in an online cyber alumni and matchmaking service designed to provide an easy way for our members to meet each other on the Web. To accomplish this, our members create their own unique profiles and our matching technology provides them matches based on their pre-selected criteria. In order to do this, we must ask for certain personal information. None of the information we gather can be used by the public (visitors, other members, or anyone not employed by batchmates.com or the financial institutions used to process membership charges) to identify specific individuals. 

We are a membership-based service. We collect credit card, address, or bank information only from those who choose to join. All visitors to our site may browse the site, search the ads and view any articles or features our site has to offer without entering any personal information. 

Information Collected/ Tracked by batchmates.com

Batchmates.com gathers two types of information:

  1. Information users submit to us and 
  2. Information not directly submitted by users.

**Information submitted to Batchmates.com**

There are two types of user-submitted information we collect: Public and Private. We define Public information as personal information that may be displayed on the site, such as gender, age and height, but cannot be linked to a particular user. Private information is defined as any information that allows others to contact a user other than through batchmates.com or allows the collection of information about the user other than what is displayed on the site.

**Public:**  To accomplish our goal of bringing friends and compatible people together, we must gather personal information, which may or may not include: customer-specified batchmates.com username, gender, age, ethnic background, appearance, religion, income range, occupation, preference/ lifestyle information and general geographic location. Much of this information is optional, and meant to be seen by members and visitors to the site but cannot be used to identify a specific member by name, address, etc. 

**Private:** This information is gathered from members and guests who apply for the various services our site offers. This information includes, but is not limited to: email address, first name, last name, birth date, credit card number or checking account information for payment, a user-specified password, mailing address, zip code and telephone number.

**Surveys & Contests:** From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, and age).

**Batchmates.com Affiliate Partners:** The Affiliate Partner program is a vehicle for other friends & relationship-based sites to link to batchmates.com. No personal member information is exchanged with the Affiliate Partner. It simply establishes a business relationship with the partner. Affiliate Partners may not view or access private information on batchmates.com subscribers.

**Information not Directly Submitted by Users to batchmates.com Aggregate:** This is information we collect that is not personally identifiable, such as browser type and IP address. This information is gathered for all users to the site and is used for general management of the site.

**How does Batchmates.com share Information Obtained?**

**Information users submit to Match.com**

**Public:** Public information supplied by the user is intended to be viewed by visitors to the site. This information is used by visitors for searching and matching purposes. Public information cannot be used to identify a specific member by name, address, etc. 

**Surveys & Contests: **Contact and other information collected for contests will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information collected will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

**Batchmates.com’s Affiliate Partners:** Information submitted by the Affiliate Partner is used for establishing and maintaining a business relationship. No personal or business information is shared outside the relationship between Match.com and the Affiliate Partner. Affiliate Partners may not view or access private information on batchmates.com subscribers.

**Information that users do not submit to us**

**Aggregate:** We use your server, IP address, and browser-type related information in the general administration of our website.

**Sharing of the Information this Site Gathers/ Tracks**

Except where you are expressly informed otherwise or as described immediately below, we do not sell, rent, share, trade or give away any of your personal information except to the financial institution that processes your credit card or check transaction unless required by law or for the protection of your membership.

If you register with Batchmates.com through one of our co-branded versions, your registration and profile information may be shared with the co-branding partner solely for the purpose of fulfilling the services provided by the co-branded site and any related promotional offers. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of the co-branded partner for questions about their use of your personally identifiable information and how you can modify or delete it.

Links with other sites

This site contains links to other websites. Please be aware that Batchmates.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of other Web sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Information on Use of Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on batchmates.com site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects a cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas on our site. We occasionally use cookies to anonymously track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site or for advertising tracking purposes. In addition, cookies may be used on our site to allow enhanced capabilities such as chat. We do not and will not use cookies to collect private information from any user.

**Info on Correcting/ Updating or Removing Information**

Batchmates.com gives users several options for modifying or removing their information from our database please visit the **My Page** or **contact us**.

**Changes in Batchmates.com Privacy Policy**

If we change our privacy policy, we will prominently post a link to those changes on our Homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner, and we will then use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

**What about Security of your personal information?**

Batchmates.com takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line. 

When our registration/ order process asks users to enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry- SSL. This is done by our payment gateway partner.

While we or our payment gateway partners use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example a billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. 

If you have any questions about the security at our website, please **contact us**.

**What about Email Choice/ Opt-out?**

Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from our partners may opt-out of receiving these communications by following the instructions contained in the email or by logging-in and changing their email options in the My Page section of the site.

**How to contact Batchmates.com?**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please **contact us**.
